我是奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来只有一个目标
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
To save my city.
但要达到目标  我不能像过去一样成为凶手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了纪念我的朋友  我只能伪装成另一个人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
成为另一个存在
I must be something else.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
她是我女儿  海伦娜
This is my daughter, Helena.
她父亲杀了她的未婚夫的时候
When her father killed her fiance,
她就已经变得既黑暗又扭曲了
she changed into something dark and twisted.
我爸爸不配得到第二次机会
My father doesn't deserve a second chance--
新的人生
a second life.
这是学会控制你的力量
This is about learning to control your strength.
奥利  结束了  我们得离开这艘船
Ollie, it's over! We got to get off this ship!
雨果·曼海姆
Hugo Mannheim.
因为诈骗  勒索  谋杀被通缉
Warrants out for racketeering, extortion, murder--
黑手党重要人物
The goombah trifecta.
但他从来不单独行动  所以自己小心点
But he never travels alone, so watch your back,
也照顾好自己的同伴
watch your partner's back.
出发吧
Let's go.
谢谢你今晚帮我照看我爸
Thanks for helping me keep watch over my dad tonight.
只要斯莱德还逍遥法外  我们两家就都不安全
As long as Slade's out there, neither of our families are safe.
星城警局  把武器放在地上
This is the SCPD! Put your weapons on the ground!
快快快
Move, move, move!
不许动
Freeze!
走
Go.
快走
Go!
弗兰克·波提纳尔
Frank Bertinelli.
我女儿派你来杀我吗
My daughter sent you to kill me.
绿箭  第二季第十七集
爸爸  你没事吧  受伤了吗
Dad, are you all right? Are you hurt?
我没事  亲爱的
Yeah, I'm fine, sweetheart.
我知道你不信
Listen, I know you don't exactly believe
对嫌疑犯读米兰达法则这一套
in reading perps their Mirandas,
但你不能直接把人扔出窗外
but you can't just toss a guy out of a window.
他打伤了你
He shot you.
我这不没事吗
And I'm still here, ain't I?
下次自己克制一点
Just next time, show a little restraint.
我那样就很克制了
That was me showing restraint.
警探  我们有另一个问题
Detective. We have another problem.
我知道  弗兰克·波提纳尔被拘留
Yeah, I know. With Frank Bertinelli in custody,
女老大回市里就只是时间问题
it's just a matter of time before she-ro is back in town.
她是谁
Who is she?
海伦娜·波提纳尔
Helena Bertinelli.
黑手党老大弗兰克·波提纳尔的女儿
Daughter of mafia boss Frank Bertinelli.
我喜欢称呼她为  奥利弗的神经前女友
Or as I like to call her, Oliver's psycho ex-girlfriend
执意报复她的父亲
hell-bent on revenge against her father.
前女友
Ex-girlfriend?
你就听到这个词了吗
That's what you took from that sentence?
等等  她为什么这么想杀她爸爸
Wait, why does she want her father killed so badly?
他派人杀了她的未婚夫
He had her fiance murdered.
-她想报复  -让我想到了
- She wants payback. - Puts the many fights
我和我爸爸吵过的架
I've had with my father in perspective.
过去一年里  我一直在监视海伦娜
I've been keeping tabs on Helena over the past year.
最后一次出现是一个月之前
Last known sighting was a month ago,
在巴勒莫[意大利城市]
Palermo.
她很忙啊
She's been busy.
如果你说的"忙"
If by "Busy,"
是指酷刑折磨和杀害那些
you mean torturing and killing mafiosos
可能知道她父亲下落的黑手党成员
that might know where her father is.
逮捕波提纳尔一事上了新闻
Bertinelli's arrest just hit the wires.
在海伦娜订机票赶回来之前
How long do you think we
你觉得我们还有多少时间
have before Helena books a ticket back home?
来吧
Go ahead.
斯莱德  拜托
Slade, please--
为什么还不走
Why aren't we moving yet?
我们想办法修复了船体
We managed to repair the hull.
但是引擎损伤太严重了
But the engine is too damaged.
-那就修好它  -我做不到
- So fix it. - I can't.
我不知道怎么修
I don't know how!
那就去找会修的
Then find somebody who does.
大家好  我是劳蕾尔  是个酒瘾者
Hi, my name's Laurel, I'm an alcoholic.
你好  劳蕾尔
Hi, Laurel.
今天实际上是我第二次参加会议
And this is actually my second meeting today.
这个...
It's just, uh...
这个真的太难了  因为我不知道
It's just so hard, because I don't know
一整天该做什么好
what to do with myself all day.
我是个律师
I'm a lawyer,
我曾是律师
well, I... was...a lawyer.
我很喜欢这份工作
I loved it.
但我想我更喜欢喝酒
But I guess I loved drinking more.
我知道我和你们一起在这里时  我能做到
I know that I can make it down here with all of you.
但是我不知道在外面能不能做到
I just...I'm not sure I can make it out there.
总之
Anyway.
谢谢大家让我分享
Thank you for letting me share.
唐纳  来电
星城法院
谢谢你过来
Thanks for coming.
抱歉是那样的结局
Sorry about the way things ended here.
不用道歉
No, don't be.
你帮了我  亚当
You did me a favor, Adam.
那是我降到低谷的唯一方法
It was the only way I was going to hit bottom,
而且
and...
而且我做到了
and I did.
不如你现在帮我个忙吧
How about you do me a favor now...
回来工作
Come back to work.
你想要我回来吗
You want me back?
我在找人处理这起刚到的案子
I'm looking for someone to try this case that just came in,
老实说  我第一个想到的就是你
and honestly, yours was the first name that came to mind.
酒吧还要对我提出制裁呢
I'm still facing sanctions from the bar.
我在纪律委员会有个朋友
Oh, I got a buddy on the disciplinary committee.
我帮你摆平这件事了
I squared things for you.
昨晚星城警局进行突袭  逮捕了弗兰克·波提纳
An SCPD raid last night brought in Frank Bertinelli.
他回星城来收债
He came back to Starling to collect on some old debts.
地检办很明确地
Now, the DA's office is clear
要控告他  你来控告他
to prosecute him; for you to prosecute him.
谢谢你的提议  亚当  但为什么是我
I appreciate the offer, Adam, but why me?
你在创新联合会时胜诉的
Well, there are rico counts
反诈骗腐败组织集团犯罪案件数
that your time at CNRI
让你有资格胜任
make you ideally suited for.
劳蕾尔  这是一起案子
Laurel, it's a case.
如果你想要  它就是你的
If you want it, it's yours.
但前提是你得准备好
But only if you're ready.
威登酒吧
今天是什么日子
What's the special occasion?
我领工资了  所以
I got paid. So, you know,
如果你觉得还不够好
if you don't think it's nice enough,
你只能怪自己
you only have yourself to blame
不给我涨工资了
for not giving me that raise.
罗伊  我很喜欢
Roy, I love it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
等  等我一下
Hey, give me-- give me a second,
我忘记订货了
I forgot to put an order in.
好的
OK.
有新进展吗
Hey, what's going on?
我找到海伦娜的未婚夫迈克尔·斯塔顿了
I got a line on Michael Statton, Helena's fiancé.
费利西蒂  他死了五年了
Felicity, he's been dead for five years.
所以他昨晚租了
Which makes the fact that
一辆车这件事尤其令人印象深刻
he rented a car last night very impressive.
那是海伦娜
That's Helena.
有车载卫星定位系统  我黑进去了
The car's got GPS, I hacked into it.
好吧  她在往星城开
Yeah. She's heading straight for Starling City.
你准备好出外勤了吗
You ready to get back in the field?
我以为你永远都不会问呢
I thought you'd never ask.
一切都结束了 海伦娜
It's over, Helena.
从车里出来
Get out of the car!
枪
Gun!
别杀我
Don't hurt me!
退后
Stand down.
Stand...down!
-别杀我  -闪电
- Don't hurt me! - Speedy!
够了
Enough!
他只是海伦娜布置的诱饵
He's just Helena's decoy.
她在哪里
Where is she?
我不知道
I don't know!
有个小妞给我钱让我开这辆车兜风
Some chick just paid me to take the car for a joy ride.
我发誓
I swear!
求你们不要杀我
Please don't kill me.
我下个月就要结婚了
I'm getting married next month.
开你的车
Just drive.
据星城警局的线索  载海伦娜进城的人
According to the SCPD, the guy that gave Helena
是一名在星城大学
a ride into town is
专攻政治社会学的22岁学生
a 22-year-old poly sci major at SCU,
他还加入了一个兄弟会
and a member of gamma tau,
这就能解释
which totally explains the whole
我不知道在帮助并教唆一名重犯的戏码了
"I didn't know I was aiding and abetting a known felon" thing.
只要是女的就能让兄弟会的人做任何事
Anyone with boobs can get a frat boy to do anything.
-我曾经是兄弟会成员  -我不说了
- I was a frat boy. - I rest my case.
至少她没杀他  还不错
At least she didn't kill him. That's something.
这么克制不是海伦娜的风格
It's not like Helena to show restraint.
听上去你好像很了解她啊
It sounds like you have a type.
继续注意警察的动向
Keep tabs on the police.
如果警方有她的线索  马上通知我
Let me know if they get any leads on her.
我去找几个线人问问
I'll do some canvassing.
-你还好吗  -还好
- You OK? - Yeah.
明天这个时候  就会像什么都没发生过了
By this time tomorrow, it'll be like nothing happened.
那是米拉库鲁的优点之一
That's one upside to Mirakuru.
唯一的优点
The only one.
我知道你打算说什么
Look, I know what you're going to say.
我昨晚已经控制得很好了
I had it under control last night.
是啊  好到我差点就又射你一箭了
Yeah, so under control that I almost put another arrow in you.
我已经打算后退了  但你不给我机会
I was going to back off, but you never gave me a chance.
唯一让你迅速清醒的事
The only thing that snapped you out of it
就是我提起西娅
was when I brought up Thea.
那就是你冲我喊我闪电的原因
That's why you called me Speedy.
我  我以为你想给我起个昵称
I--I thought you were trying to give me a nickname.
但我要声明  别叫我闪电
But for the record, don't call me Speedy.
记住了
Noted.
罗伊  你是个危险的人
Roy, you're dangerous.
我以为我是在帮你控制它
I thought I was helping you control it.
你是的  我是说
You are. I mean,
我看到一碗水就忍不住去拍它
I can't look at a bowl of water without slapping it.
数周以来你第一次出外勤
The first time that you're out in the field in weeks,
你就  准备好杀人了吗
and...you're ready to kill somebody?
这可不行
Come on.
对不起  我几个月前就应该让你这么做的
I'm sorry, I should have asked you to do this months ago.
做什么
Asked me to do what?
远离西娅
Stay away from Thea.
不  我  我做不到
No, I--I can't.
她在你身边的时候非常不安全
She's not safe when she's around you.
你生气失控时
I'm not sure anybody is
谁在你身边都不安全
when you lose yourself to this rage.
你爱她
You love her.
所以你要按我说的做
And that's why you're going to do what I'm asking.
太惊人了
Such a big uh-oh.
海伦娜
Helena?
是劳蕾尔
Laurel.
检察官亚当·唐纳宣布
ADA Adam Donner announced
在短暂的休假之后劳蕾尔·兰斯
the return of Laurel Lance to the D.A.'s office
正式回归地方检察官办公室
after a brief sabbatical.
重大新闻
她将主导对波提纳尔的起诉
She will lead the prosecution of Mr. Bertinelli.
陪审团的选定从今天开始
Jury selection starts today.
你来这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我从新闻上得知你拿到了几个大案子
I heard you picked up some big new case on the news.
你怎么不给我打电话
How come you didn't call me?
我想打的  但一切都发生的太快了
I was going to, but it all happened so fast.
再说  我觉得你和爸爸不会让我
Plus, I thought you and dad would try and talk me out of
这么快就重新开始工作
going back to work so soon.
你就是为这个来的
Which is why you're here.
我很担心你
I'm just worried about you.
如果你担心我会犯错误
If you're worried I'm going to slip,
我每天依然要参加两场会议  而且
I'm still going to two meetings a day, and--
劳蕾尔  不是指那个
Laurel, it's not that.
所有人都知道波提纳尔是个什么货色
Everybody knows what kind of guy Bertinelli is.
更不用说他那个已经准备回星城来
And not to mention his completely psychotic daughter,
杀掉他的精神病女儿
who's already on her way back to Starling City to kill him.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
我不知道
I don't.
我只是希望你安全
I just want you to be safe.
我爱你的体贴
And I love you for caring.
但是莎拉  你从来没见过我当律师
But Sara, you've never seen me be a lawyer before.
我真的很擅长这份工作
And I am really good at it.
我也很怀念
And I miss it.
我得走了
I have to run.
庭审可不能迟到
I can't be late for court.
这里真是比货船好多了啊
Yeah, this is much better than the freighter.
亨德里克  你喜欢在船上的话可以游回去
You prefer boat, Hendrik, feel free to swim back.
莎拉说奥利弗在这活了一年多
Sara said Oliver survived here for over a year.
我们也可以的
We can do the same.
除非艾沃和他的手下找到我们
Unless Ivo and his men come find us.
我们不知道船上发生了什么
We don't know what happened on the boat.
谁还活着  谁已经死了
Who's alive and who's dead.
莎拉  你在吗
Sara, are you there?
斯莱德  奥利弗...
Slade! Is Oliver...
他很痛苦  是的
He's in pain, yes.
但他现在依然活着
But he's still breathing--for now.
斯莱德  听着  你赢了  行了吧
Slade, listen, you won, OK?
亚马逊号归你了
You have the "Amazo."
放了奥利弗吧  你可以把我们留在这里
Just let Oliver go, and then you can leave us here!
这就是我的问题  莎拉
Well, here's my problem, Sara.
我走不了
I can't leave.
-为什么  -我们交火的时候
- Why not? - During our assault,
船的发动机损坏了
the ship's engine was damaged.
无法航行了
She won't sail.
很不幸交火时我还把工程师杀了
During the attack, unfortunately I decapitated the engineer.
所以怎么处理我们的问题呢  莎拉
So what can we do about our problem, Sara?
你想要奥利弗回去
You want Oliver back,
而我需要一个有能力修船的人
and I need someone qualified to fix this boat.
为了奥利弗
For Oliver's sake,
我希望亨德里克先生跟你在一起
I sure hope a Mr. Hendrik is there with you.
非致命的箭
Non-lethal arrows?
玩这种小孩的玩意可不是你的风格
It's not like you to play with kid gloves.
罗伊怎么样了
How's Roy?
跟海伦娜一样  他不太喜欢我作为导师的技巧
Like Helena, he is not too pleased with my skills as a mentor.
劳蕾尔不愿放弃那案子
Laurel won't drop the case.
她现在就在去法庭的路上
She's headed to court right now.
-你要去哪儿  -去法庭
- Where are you going? - To the courthouse.
你忘带你的小孩子箭头了
Well, hey, you forgot your baby arrows.
我明白你那套不杀人的主张
Look, I get your whole no killing spree,
但如果最后要救劳蕾尔  杀掉海伦娜
but if it comes down to saving Laurel or killing Helena--
莎拉  并不只有这两个选择
Sara, those aren't the only two choices.
斯莱德威胁你的家人的时候
Well, you were happy enough to let Dig take the kill shot
你也高兴地让狄格下了杀手
when it was Slade threatening your family.
这不一样
This is different.
我辜负了海伦娜
I failed Helena.
"女杀手"是我创造出来的
I created the "Huntress".
是啊  斯莱德也是你创造出来的
Yeah, well, you created Slade, too.
你说得对
You're right.
但一旦涉及我们的家人
But when it comes to our families...
我们俩头脑就都不清楚
neither one of us thinks clearly.
所以你得留在这里
Which is why you have to stay here.
奥利
Ollie.
我不能留下
I can't.
我不会让劳蕾尔出任何事的
I'm not going to let anything happen to Laurel.
我也爱她
I love her, too.
你们觉得呢
What do you guys think?
我觉得如果"女杀手"出现
Oh, I think if the Huntress shows up,
你应该打爆她
you should totally kick her ass.
拜托别告诉我你也很担心我
Please don't tell me you're worried about me, too.
不是  我只是想看看审判
No, I just wanted to watch the trial.
我听说那个律师很特别
I heard the prosecutor was something special.
真奇怪
That's odd.
他们为什么带他从正门进来
Why are they bringing him in through the front entrance?
所有人都趴下
Everybody get down!
你好啊  爸爸
Hi, dad.
抱歉我来晚了  你可真不好找啊
Sorry I'm late, but you're a hard man to track down.
但你回到星城很合适
But it's fitting that you came back to Starling.
这是一切开始的地方
Where it all began.
是你杀了迈克尔的地方
Where you killed Michael.
我差一点就为你感到抱歉了
You know, I almost feel sorry for you.
海伦娜
Helena...
住手
Stop this.
奥利弗  你知道我不能
Oliver, you know I can't.
那你还在等什么
Well, what are you waiting for?
我说  你还在等什么
I said, what are you waiting for?!
海伦娜·波提纳尔  把武器放下
Helena Bertinelli, put down your weapons
把手举过头顶
and place your hands above your head.
这么说这是一个大陷阱...
So this was a big trap...
你就是诱饵
with you as the bait.
他们给你什么好处
What did they offer you?
他们什么好处也不用给我
Ah, they didn't have to offer me anything.
放弃吧  波提纳尔女士  大楼被包围了
Give up, Miss Bertinelli, the building's surrounded.
你一直都怎么教导我的来着  爸爸
What was it you always taught me, daddy?
做好万全的准备
Be prepared for anything.
动手
Now.
抓住人质  后退
Take hostages, and fall back.
别开枪  别开枪  他们手里有人质
Hey, hold your fire, hold your fire! They have hostages!
别开枪  重复  别开枪  他们有人质
Hold fire. Say it again, hold fire. They've taken hostages.
劳蕾尔在哪儿  劳蕾尔在哪儿  她跟你一起吗
Where's Laurel? Where's Laurel? Is she with you?
抱歉  兰斯先生  我们走散了
I'm sorry, Mr. Lance, we got separated.
她还在里面
She's still inside.
我们正在星城法院外进行直播
We are live outside the Starling City courthouse,
海伦娜·波提纳尔和不明数量的攻击者
where Helena Bertinelli and an unknown number of assailants
控制了整栋大楼
seized control of the entire building.
现在我被告知
And I'm now being told,
他们在里面控制了一些人质
they are holding a number of hostages inside.
安排狙击手带着热成像瞄准镜
I want snipers with thermals on top
在两个街区范围内的所有大楼顶部待命
of every building for a two block radius.
不应该发生这种事的  上尉
This was not how it was supposed to go down, Captain!
你跟我保证说不会有伤亡的
You promised me there wouldn't be any casualties!
这是你的注意吗  你个混蛋
This was your idea, huh? You son of a bitch!
我女儿在里面
Hey, my daughter's in there!
你们是怎么想的
What were you guys thinking,
拿那么多无辜的生命冒险
putting all those innocent lives at risk?
-听着  我是在执行命令  -命令
- Listen! I was following orders. - Orders?!
波提纳尔女士
Ms. Bertinelli.
任何人都不必死
No one has to die today.
我爸爸需要死
My father does.
除非你们把他交给我
And unless you hand him over to me,
不然我要开始杀人质了
I'm going to start killing hostages.
看吧  唐纳先生
See this, Mr. Donner,
这就是你不管戴面具的疯子的后果
is what happens when you let freaks with masks run wild.
把他们带出去
Get them the hell out of here.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
是我妈打来的
It's my mom.
警探
Detective.
海伦娜·波提纳尔控制了十名人质
Helena Bertinelli just took ten hostages.
劳蕾尔就是其中之一
Laurel's one of them.
我知道现在的情况
Yeah, I'm aware of the situation.
奥利弗  你在哪里  你还好吗
Oliver, where are you? Are you ok?
我以奥利弗的身份和兰斯在一起
I'm with Lance as Oliver,
他刚刚打给绿箭侠了
and he just called the Arrow.
越来越难搞清
It's getting really hard to
谁知道谁的秘密身份了
keep track of who knows whose secret identity.
费利西蒂  劳蕾尔还在法院里
Felicity, Laurel is still inside the courthouse.
你需要什么  奥利弗
What do you need, Oliver?
-我的战袍  -这就来
- My work clothes. - I'm on it.
让莎拉接电话
Put Sara on the phone.
她不在这里
She's not here.
她去哪了
Where is she?
你是好人吗
Are you one of the good guys?
不  但我和好人是朋友
No, but I'm friends with them.
威登酒吧
-看着点  -去你的
- Dude, watch it. - Screw you!
西娅  我们分手吧
Thea, we need to break up.
什么
What?!
不要
No.
不要是什么意思
What do you mean, no?
西娅  我要和你分手
Thea, I'm breaking up with you.
不  不行
No, you're not.
你不能强迫我和你约会
You can't make me date you.
罗伊  昨天你才用全部积蓄
Roy, yesterday you gave me a bracelet
买了个手镯送给我
worth every dime that you had,
现在却要和我分手了
And now what, you want to end things?
你最近显然不太好过
Look, you're clearly going through something right now,
我不会让你一个人撑着的
and I'm not going to let you go through it alone.
我会永远陪着你
I'm always going to be here for you.
不好意思  西娅  私人派对那个男的
Sorry, Thea. The guy from the private party
说我们上错了伏特加  在发飙呢
said we stocked the wrong vodka, and he's freaking me out.
我们待会再谈  好吗
Look, we'll talk about this later, ok?
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
我太笨了
I'm so stupid.
你不会想那么做的
You don't want to do that.
相信我
Oh, no, trust me.
我需要
I do.
那你的戒酒的事怎么办
What about your sobriety?
你怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
你钥匙圈上的那个"A"
The "A" chip on your keychain.
30天
30 days.
戒酒30天
你知道我今天为什么会来吗
Do you even know why I'm here today?
原来我就是个装饰
Turns out I'm decoration.
可有可无的装饰
Expendable decoration.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
整个庭审就是个幌子
This whole trial was a sham.
我早该想到的
I should have seen it.
莎拉是对的
Sara was right.
莎拉是
Sara, she's...
我妹妹
she's my sister.
她说我还没有准备好
She said that I wasn't ready to come back, and...
我以为那是她保护过度
I just thought she was being overprotective.
姐妹之间总是这样
Well, sisters can be like that.
你真该见见我的姐妹
You should meet mine.
她受了很多苦
She's gone through a lot.
她一定很坚强
She must have been so strong.
我只是
I just...
我想让她和我自己看到
I wanted to show her, show myself...
我也依然很坚强
that I was still strong, too.
那展现给我看吧
So show me.
我们走
Let's go.
你在哪里
Where are you?
在里面  我找到劳蕾尔·兰斯了
Inside. I've got Laurel Lance,
她没事
she's ok.
是绿箭侠吗
Is that the Arrow?
我在向南侧的出口走
I'm headed to an egress point in the south wing.
等等
Wait.
其他人质怎么办
What about the other hostages?
你就放着他们不管了吗
You're just going to leave them?
我得救你出去
Look, I need to get you to safety.
我不明白  我有什么特殊的
I don't understand! What is so special about me?
怎么回事
What's going on?
她不愿意走
She won't leave.
我了解海伦娜
I know Helena.
她会把他们都杀了的
She's going to kill all of those people,
那些无辜的人
innocent people.
是你让我展现自己的坚强
You wanted me to show you I'm strong.
我现在就给你看  我要留下来
This is me being strong. I'm staying.
你到底要不要帮我
Are you going to help me or not?
快把她带出来
Get her out of there now!
我又不能直接把她打晕
It's not like I can just knock her out.
我不想你和海伦娜交锋
I don't want you engaging Helena.
怎么  你是怕她会做什么吗
What, you're afraid of what she'll do...
还是我会做什么事
or what I'll do?
莎拉  你不是个杀手
Sara...you're not a killer.
我该是什么就是什么
I am what I need to be.
莎拉  你能听到吗
Sara, did you hear me?
我听得到
I heard you.
亨德里克不在
Hendrik's not here.
有人想跟你打个招呼
There's someone I'd like you to say hello to.
什么都别给他  莎拉
Don't give him anything, Sara.
奥利
Ollie!
最后一次机会
One last chance.
奥利弗换亨德里克
Oliver for Hendrik.
我说过了  亨德里克没有
I told you! Look, Hendrik, he didn't make it
活着到岛上  他淹死了
to the island, he drowned.
想想一年前  你不过是个大学女孩
To think it was only a year ago, you were a little college girl,
绕着男生转
fretting about boys.
你什么意思
What's your point?
你可不会骗人
You're not a good liar.
斯莱德  求你  住手
Slade! Stop, please!
他是你的朋友
Look, he's your friend!
刚刚就是电流穿过我朋友的声音
That is the sound of electricity surging through my friend.
准确来说是5毫安
Five milliamps, to be exact.
7毫安能使心脏停跳
Seven causes cardiac arrest.
奥利弗刚才在6毫安的时候晕过去了
Oliver just passed out with six milliamps.
一小时后如果亨德里克没被带到我面前
He'll be delivered with the fatal blow of seven
我就用7毫安送他上路
in one hour if hendrik is not standing here by my side!
我死也不会回去的
There's no way in hell I'm going back there.
我有次差点结婚了
I was almost married once.
已经过了一小时了
It's been an hour,
我可是说话算话的
and I'm a woman of my word.
不信问我爸爸
Just ask my father.
会没事的
Everything's going to be ok.
小心后面
Behind you!
奥利弗真的很喜欢让他的女朋友变装
Oliver sure does like to dress up his girls.
你还好吗
You all right?
劳蕾尔她还在那
Laurel! She's still in there.
很高兴再次见到你  劳蕾尔
Nice to see you again, Laurel.
海伦娜  听我说
Helena, listen to me.
-这一切必须结束  -我同意
- This has to end. - I agree.
我父亲被装进棺材就结束
And it ends with my father in a box.
警察不会把你父亲交出来的
The police are never going to hand over your father!
是的  他们不会
No, they won't.
所以要由你把他交给我
That's why you're going to do it.
很简单
Simple trade--
用我父亲来交换劳蕾尔
my father for Laurel.
伙计们
Hey, guys?
我们还需要一些伏特加
We need more vodka.
好吧
Ok...
我自己去拿
I'll get it myself.
你们要带我去哪儿
Where are you taking me?
安全屋
Safe house.
听着  正门被记者的围攻了
Listen, front's mobbed with reporters.
把波提纳尔从后门带出去
Let's take Bertinelli out the back.
把车开过来
Bring the van around.
好吧
Ow! All right.
-怎么回事  -别怕
- Whoa! What the hell? - Don't worry about it.
-到底怎么回事  -快上车
- What's going on? - Just get in the van!
特警队已经做好准备闯进法院
SWAT's getting ready to breach the courthouse.
那我们现在就去换人
Then we make the trade now.
听着  我可不会因为弗兰克死了而失眠
Listen, I'm not going to lose any sleep over Frank.
你要把他交给他女儿吗
But are you really going to serve him up to his daughter?
不
No.
今晚谁也不会死
No one dies tonight.
你还好吗
Are you ok?
会没事的
Everything's going to be fine.
我说过  不许讲话
I said...no talking.
我们那天晚上谈过
We talked that night.
你  奥利弗  汤米和我
You, Oliver, Tommy, and I.
吃晚饭的时候
At dinner.
我记得你说你的未婚夫被杀了
I remember you telling me your fiance was killed.
真的很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
你这么说我们就是好朋友了吗
Does this make us girlfriends?
不
No.
但是我明白失去一个人的滋味
But I know what it's like to lose someone.
可怜的劳蕾尔
Poor Laurel.
汤米把你甩了吗
Did Tommy dump you?
没有
No.
他死了
He died.
我始终放不下这件事
And I couldn't deal with it.
所以我开始酗酒
So I became a drunk.
每当遇到问题
Every problem I had,
我就用药片或者酒精来解决
I solved with a pill or a drink.
我的朋友和家人们都试图帮我
My friends and my family,
但我据他们千里之外
they tried to help me, but I wouldn't let them.
你不必这么做的  海伦娜
You don't have to do this, Helena.
现在还不算太晚
It's not too late.
我需要这么做
Yes, I do.
一旦黑暗驻进了你的内心
Because once you let the darkness inside,
它就永远不会出去了
it never comes out.
海伦娜  你父亲在我这
Helena. I have your father.
我需要一个四人小组  钻石阵型
I want four men teams, diamond formations.
快速移动  精确狙击
Move fast, shoot sharp.
还有一件事  治安维持者不是法律
One more thing-- vigilantes are not the law.
如果他们带着面具出现  就给他们一枪
If they're wearing a mask, they get a bullet.
开始行动
Let's move out.
波提纳尔立刻把手举起来
Hands up, bertinelli! Do it now!
求求你别杀我  求求你
Please don't kill me! Please!
她告诉我
She--she told me--
如果我不穿上它  她就杀了我
She told me to wear it or she'd kill me!
她在哪
Where the hell is she?!
别那么害怕  劳蕾尔  你或许能活下来呢
Don't look so scared, Laurel. You might just live through this.
你们要把我交到我女儿手里吗
So you're just going to hand me over to my daughter?
我还以为你们是好人
I thought you were the good guys!
闭嘴
Shut up.
还记得我说过关于克制的事吗
Remember all that stuff I said about restraint?
忘了吧
Forget about it.
你不能通过变成海伦娜那样的人来阻止她
You can't stop someone like Helena by becoming her.
怎样能保护我爱的人  我就怎样做
I'll do what I have to to protect someone I love.
亨德里克  拜托  把枪放下
Hendrik, please, put the gun down!
为什么  那样你就可以把我送回那个地狱去了吗
Why? So you can send me back to that hell hole?
我可不这样想
I don't think so!
我们任何人都不能决定我们之中谁活谁死
It's not for any of us to decide who lives and dies.
但亨德里克这种情况  我愿意破例一次
But in Hendrik's case, I'd be willing to make an exception.
我要离开这  别阻止我
I'm leaving. Don't stop me.
说得倒好  你是不会开枪杀我的
Good at talking, but you will not kill me.
那你就试试
Let's find out.
长官  我们收到兰斯女士手机的信号了
Sir, we've got a ping off Ms. Lance's cell phone.
她一定带着电话
She must still have it on her.
在哪里
Where?
在盖尔街和西蒙街交汇的一个机械商店里
A machine shop at Gail street and Simone.
需要我们赶过去吗
Should we rally up there?
不需要  留守在你们的位置
Negative. Hold your location.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
警官  在这里好好镇守
Sergeant, keep this position.
对你来说真讽刺啊  爸爸
Well, this is irony for you, dad.
吉米·戴戈斯诺的尸体
Didn't you have Jimmy D'agostino's body
就被你埋在隔壁的地下吧
buried under the building next door?
抱歉  女儿
I'm sorry, my girl.
现在你就要死了  我肯定你的确抱歉
Now you're about to die, I'm sure you are.
不
No.
我是对那个我曾经带着去芭蕾课的小女孩抱歉
I'm sorry for that little girl i used to take to ballet class.
一起去滑雪旅行的小女孩
Go on ski trips with.
我曾帮着做数学作业的小女孩
The one I used to help with her math homework.
她讨厌数学
Oh, she hated math.
抱歉我为她带来了这么多伤害
Sorry that I caused her so much hurt,
而她带给我如此多的欢乐
'cause she brought me so much joy.
海伦娜
Helena!
不要杀他
Don't kill him.
那样你就再也回不去了
You can never come back from that.
太晚了
It's too late.
我已经回不去了
I'm already gone.
再见  爸爸
Bye, dad.
可恶的治安维持者
Damn vigilantes!
你们触犯了法律
You went above the law!
上次出现这种情况时  我把你从窗户扔了出去
Last time this happened, I threw you out a window.
我当时有所保留呢
I was holding back.
但是这次不会了
I won't do that again.
不
No!
你不是杀人犯
You're not a killer.
你根本不知道真正的我是什么样子  劳蕾尔
You don't know who I am, Laurel, not really.
那就展现给我看
Then show me.
不
No...
应该是我的
It was supposed to be me.
应该是我来动手的
It was supposed to me who did it.
行了  波提纳尔  够了
All right, Bertinelli, that's enough.
快走
Go.
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
我们家族为警察的退休基本捐了一大笔钱
My family makes a generous donation to the policemen's retirement fund.
所以我偶尔会让他们帮个小忙
And every once in a while, I get to call in a favor.
那你应该让他们把我
Hmm. Maybe you could ask them to send me
送去热带的监狱
to prison somewhere tropical.
我以为我的感觉会有所不同
You know, I thought I'd feel different.
但他死后  我的感觉没变
Now that he's dead, but I don't.
你一直跟我说
And you always told me that...
杀了他也无济于事
killing him wouldn't change anything.
你说得对
You were right.
但是我也有错
But I was wrong, too.
什么错了
About what?
我以为我能帮你
I thought I could help you.
能阻止你杀人
Stop you from being a killer,
但是
but...
我才刚刚开始
I was just starting.
我以前也是个杀人犯
And I was a killer, too.
那现在呢
And what are you now?
我在努力变好
I'm trying to be better.
虽然很蠢  但是
It's so stupid, but...
我一直在想  既然他死了
I keep thinking, now that he's dead,
我父亲和迈克尔在一起了  而我...
my father and Michael are together, and...
我仍然在这里
I'm still here.
孤身一人
Alone.
你不是孤身一人
You're not alone.
你在对我做什么
What are you doing to me?
罗马时期
In Roman times,
罪犯会被做上标记
a criminal was branded
以让世人分辨出他的罪行
to identify his crimes to the world
也永远提醒他自己的所作所为
and to forever remind him of what he'd done.
莎朵的背上就有这个纹身
Shado wore this tattoo on her back.
你的余生就一直背负着这个纹身吧
Now you shall wear it for the rest of your life,
不论你的生命有多么短暂
however short that may be.
弗林
Flynn.
你好  莎拉
Hello, Sara.
希望你做出了正确的选择
I hope you've made the right choice.
是的
Yes.
我代表整个地检办办公室
Look, on behalf of the entire DA's office,
向你道歉
I have to apologize.
亚当·唐纳已经不在这里工作了
Adam Donner's employment here has been terminated.
我们之前真的不知道他有什么阴谋诡计
Obviously we had no idea what he was plotting.
但愿如此
I would hope not.
很不幸  亚当没有权利
Unfortunately, Adam was not authorized
让你回来工作
to offer you your job back.
抱歉
I'm sorry,
但是一切都没变
but nothing has changed.
不  变了
Yes, it has.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你要把工作还给我  凯特
You are going to rehire me, Kate.
除非你想去向媒体解释
Unless you feel like explaining to the press
自己手下的区助理检察官
that your own assistant district attorney
就是今晚人质危机事件的幕后黑手
was the brilliant mastermind behind tonight's hostage crisis.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
不得不说  真让我刮目相看啊
I have to say, I am impressed.
我还以为你不会用威胁这么肮脏的手段
I would have thought blackmail was a little dark for you.
最近有人告诉我
Someone recently told me,
一旦让黑暗驻进自己的内心
once you let the darkness inside,
它就永远不会出去了
it never comes out.
威登酒吧
你还在这里干什么
What are you still doing up here?
思考
Thinking.
哭泣
Crying.
我和罗伊...
Roy and I are...
怎么回事
What happened?
我抓到他跟一个贱人一起
I caught him with some slut.
就在那边
Right over there, actually.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
他那样做是为了把我推开
He was doing it to push me away,
这下起作用了
which clearly worked.
我  我不知道为什么
I just... I don't know why.
为什么大家说实话
Why is it so hard for everyone
就那么难呢
just to tell the truth?
罗伊根本就不跟我说实话
I mean, Roy can't even tell me the truth
不告诉我到底为什么跟我分手
of why he wants to end things with me.
妈妈  她...
Mom, she...
她守着那么多秘密
She keeps all of these secrets.
难道你...
I mean, doesn't it...
你不觉得她还有什么瞒着我们吗
Doesn't it feel like she's still keeping something from us?
我也不知道  西娅
I don't know, Thea.
你是唯一一个不撒谎骗我的  奥利
You're the only one that doesn't lie to me, Ollie.
你是我认识的人中
You're the only one I know
唯一一个不瞒着我的
who doesn't keep secrets from me.
我先走了
Just, I got to go.
我开车送你吧
Let me drive you.
不用了  我现在想一个人静一静
No, I just want to be alone right now.
她没事吧
Is she OK?
会没事的
She will be.
最终会的
Eventually.
你今晚做得很棒
You did good tonight.
英雄都会那样做的  对吗
That's what heroes do, right?
这是个危险的城市
It's a dangerous city.
你不该一个人在街上的
You shouldn't be out in the streets alone.
威尔逊先生
Mr. Wilson?
叫我斯莱德就行
Please. Call me Slade.